OREN AMEMATEKPO

(312) 914-0707 | <u>orenamema@gmail.com</u>

SUMMARY

Experienced business professional offering a blend of creative and analytical skills with over 5 years of experience. With an outstanding combination of academic and professional experience including operations analysis, financial planning, client experience, strong modeling skills Financial and data analysis, Financial statement analysis, Sensitivity analysis, Forecasting, Financial reporting and GAAP. Successfully managed several projects and demonstrated result driven abilities.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley Full Stack Web Development, November 2019 - Present

University of Notre Dame, Master of Science in Finance, May 2019

Notre Dame MS in Finance 2018 Fellowship

Northern Illinois University, Master of Business Administration (MBA), May 2012

Northern Illinois University, Bachelor of Science in Marketing, May 2011

Charles and Concetta International Marketing Award 2011

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AXA US , Chicago, IL

Senior Operations Analyst

March 2016 - Present

- Reviewed and analyzed operations processes, identified inefficiencies in current procedures and developed strategies for process improvement. Increased efficiency of repatriation planning by 20%; recommended daily assignments to increase productivity. Improved project efficiency 10% by automating data processing.
- Managed projects to identify cost containment measures and increase the quality of employees' performance. Documented findings, performed risk analysis and prepared presentations to highlight findings. Performed margin and profitability analysis on various systems including Excel.
- Created independent analyses on return of investment. Managed monthly ad hoc forecasting cycles for the operations team. Delivered clear analysis to senior management and provided recommendations to enable the team to meet monthly targets. Managed budgets and contributed in elaborating the monthly financial reports.
- Worked on cross functional teams with Finance, Marketing and HR to elaborate RFP for our clients which included reviewing payment & billing terms and services. Provided ad hoc analytical support across several business units. Assisted in the RFPs for contract renewal.
- Managed implementation of new major clients including designing and controlling costs. Performed and managed key account reconciliation. Coordinated high volume payment of all external providers.

AXA US, Chicago, IL

February 2013 - March 2016

Operations Analyst

- Delivered quality client services in a timely manner. Key Accounts: Boston Consulting Group, Blue Cross and Blue Shields. Saved the clients over \$500,000 via excel models resulting in 100% loyalty
- Successfully implemented procedures to identify clients at risk of medical assets. Advised on minimizing client risk exposure and resulted in a 30% cost saving on medical expenses. Used spreadsheet to generate monthly reports for clients detailing issues, monthly expenses and areas for improvement.

TECHNOLOGY-LANGUAGES

HTML|CSS| SQL| JavaScript|Bootstrap| JQuery| Node.js|AJAX| Github|API| JSON| Powerpoint| SQL| Sharepoint| Peoplesoft| Capital IQ| Bloomberg |Fluent in French